If you are looking for a comprehensive health
insurance plan, then both
Elevate by ICICI LBAD and Re 3.0 by Niva BPA can be
an ideal choice.  But
if you are confused about which of the two
plans is more suitable for you, then
watch this video till the end.  In this I have done
a detailed comparison of both the plans.
All the features are based
on parameters, based on their claim analysis and
based on their premium.  After watching this video,
you will be able to decide which
plan is more suitable for you.  Hello
friends, I am Ashutosh, your personal
finance coach.  Let's start the video.
ICICI LBRD is a general insurance
company which works across all verticals.
Whereas Niva is a stand-alone health
insurance company.  ICICI LBAD's
Elevate is also a flagship product and Nivab
BUPA's ReSure series like
ReSure 2.0, ReSure 3.0 and Asire have unique
features which we get to see only in NivPA.
And
all these plans with higher bonuses were first started by NIV BUPA.
So the minimum and
maximum entry age in both the plans is 18
years and there is no maximum entry age.  You
can enter any plan.
Senior citizens can also take it.
For newborn baby it is 90 days.  If there is any newborn
baby, it will be covered only after 90 days.  The sum
assured option is Rs 5 lakh to 3 crore in ICICI LBAD
and along with this we
also get an unlimited sum assured option.
Whereas in Niva Reshur 3.0, there is a
sum assured option of Rs 10 lakh in the sum assured option of Rs 5 lakh
and apart from that there is a direct unlimited sum
assured option.  Friends, this
unlimited option is the biggest USP of
this plan that now in this plan there will be no
tension of bonus, restoration or
coverage.  Unlimited means there
is no limit.  Talking about room category,
single private AC room will be applicable in ICICI LBD.
However, with the Room Modifier
rider, you can remove this and
get a room of any category.
Talking about Nivpa rhsur 3.0 Elite & Black.
Single private
AC room is available in Elite variant and
you can also choose any room or suites room in Black variant.
AYUSH treatments like Ayurvedic, Unani,
Siddha, Homeopathy are
covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  Pre and Post
Hospitalization ICC Labard 60 Days
and 180 Days.  Whereas Neev Reshore 3.0 has
cover for 60 days and 180 days.  Day Care
Treatment All Day
Care Treatment is covered in ICIC Labrador Alleviate up to Sum Assured
Resurs 3.0 We get Two Hour Hospitalization.
So indirectly all the
day care treatments are covered in this also.  Organ
donor cover is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.
Domiciliary hospitalization
is also covered up to sum assured.
In both the plans, domiciliary hospitalization is the
hospitalization that we get done at home.
Home Care Treatment At Elevate,
we have a nursing at home option.
Whereas in Aspire we have
actuals covered on S.  So home care treatment
is more versatile in this.
Up to sum assured is covered for road ambulance in both the plans.
Air ambulance up to sum
assured is covered.  But as an add on.  Whereas
Aspire Re Ashore 3.0
has inbuilt cover for Rs 5 lakh per year.  We have to take free health checkup
as an add-on and it
is also an add-on in Ratio 3.0.  Free health checkup
is not available.  Modern treatment
is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.   There
is no limit.  Lists are covered on S.
Second medical opinion
is not applicable.  Covered with in network at Elevate.
Covered in the network in Rio 3.0.
E-consultation as an add-on is available.
Unlimited times are available in Ratio 3.0.
Maternity cover will be applicable in Elevate
with a two-year waiting period and
coverage will be applicable at 10% of sum assured
maximum up to Rs 1 lakh.  There
is no maternity cover in Reshore 3.0.  If you need maternity cover
then Aspire will be a more
suitable option for you.  In that you
also get newborn baby cover up to the sum assured.
Newborn baby cover is available but it is a
part of maternity.  Twice the maternity
cover will be applicable.  There
is no newborn baby cover available.  But if you want, you can
take newborn baby cover with Aspire.
Worldwide cover
is available as an add-on in both. For Plant & Emergency
Hospitalization.  Plan variants
include Elevate only.
Classic, Select, Elite and Black in RSO 3.0.   Out
of which these two variants are of
no use because in these, only Fin
Sharing and General category rooms
are available.  So the cost of our treatment is
associated with our room.
In such a situation,
we do not have to take the policy of rooms with such high capping.
We can take the Elite variant with a single private
AC room and if you want a higher category room
then there is Black which is the highest variant.
Waiting periods are normally 30 days
initial waiting period with a
specific waiting period of two years for slow
growing diseases.  Apart from that, there is a
three year waiting period for pre-
existing conditions.
Talking about the unique benefits of both the plans, the
biggest USP of ICICI Elevate is
unlimited sum assured
and the second is power booster.  If
Unlimited Sum Assured is not taken then
we get the option of Power Booster in
which 100% bonus is given every year.  So
if you have a 10 year policy it will be 10x.  If the
policy is for 20 years then it will be 20x.
Apart from that, Infinite Care is an
add-on which gives you coverage for a particular one claim
once in a policy lifetime,
which you can use for any amount.
So, you may have a policy of Rs 10-20 lakh
, there is also a bonus of Rs 20-30 lakh and the
claim is for Rs 1 crore.  So with this option
you can exercise it.
Apart from this, when this plan was launched for unlimited restoration full and
partial related and unrelated illnesses, there
was a capping of 45 days for restoration for the
same person same illness, which was later
removed by the company.  Apart from that,
Jump Start is available to cover lifestyle diseases
like hypertension, diabetes, asthma,
hyperlipidemia, obesity, coronary
artery disease, PTCA or any other
stiffness that has occurred before one year,
you can also cover that in this plan without any waiting period.
Obesity also
covers up to 39 BMI.
Apart from that, two-hour hospitalization is there as an
add-on.  However, it covers two-hour hospitalization.
But this does not mean that
it will cover observation purposes also.
Talking about Pre Aor 3.0, Booster Plus allows
us to carry forward the basic sum assured up to 10
times.  So
you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh.  If you do
not use anything this year, the entire Rs 10 lakh will be carried
forward to the next year and
can go up to 10 times.  Apart from that, you
get the benefit of lock the clock.  This means that
if you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh at the age of 35, then
normally in every plan the
premium of your policy increases with age.
But the benefit of Lock the Clock is that
your premium will not increase until you make your first claim. It
may increase due to inflation according to age, but due to age band
your premium will not change
until you make your first claim, so this is a very
good option. For restoration, you
get the option of Rear Forever, this is also quite
unique, which we get only in Niva Bupa.
In all other plans, the
restoration is available every year from the second claim, it is
not available for the first claim, but in Rear, it becomes applicable for
life time after your first claim.
So if there is a
first claim in any year, then it will
add the restoration.  Apart from that, another unique
benefit is Day One Pre-Existing
Loading, which means that there are 142 such pre-existing
conditions which you
can avail without PD waiting period by
paying extra premium.  This is also a very good
unique benefit.  Talking about optional riders,
both the plans have many
optional riders.  Talking about the optional riders of ICICI LBAD,
Infinite Care
gives us infinite sum for a single claim.  Apart from that, there is inflation
protector which increases our basic coverage
according to inflation.
Power Booster which gives 100% bonus every year.
Domestic Air Ambulance Jump Start
that
covers the disease from Day One.  PD
Disease Co, Lifestyle Disease Co Dependent
Accommodation Claim Protector.  This is for non-
payable items, consumables.
Room modifiers
can also upgrade or downgrade rooms.
Compassionate Visit, Nursing at
Home, Maternity Cover, Newborn Baby Cover,
Vaccination of Newborn, all three are
part of the same cover.  Durable Medical
Equipment.  If you need
durable medical equipment like a
wheelchair etc. after hospitalization, you
can also cover it with this rider.
Colsens Benefit Health Checkup B Fit
is an OPD cover.  If you need OPD then
you can take Befit Rider.  Network
Advantage: This is a preferred network rider, in
which if you take this rider, the
insurance company gives you some discount.
But you have to get the treatment done
in the same preferred network.   If
you go outside the network, you have to make a
co-payment.  Apart from that, there
is cover for critical illness and personal accident.  This is a fixed benefit policy
which we can completely ignore.
Tele-consultation option to
reduce maternity waiting period.  There
is a waiting period of 2 years for maternity but
with this you can do one year.  However, this plan is
not very good for maternity.
Voluntary copayment and NRI discount.
Talking about the writers of Re Ashore 3.0, the
first cashback which gives you some cashback on renewal.
First year you get 10% off your
first year premium and thereafter
you get 5% cashback of your premium which
you can use for diagnostic tests in OPD etc.
Apart from that,
Niva Bupa One membership is available in which
it gives the benefit of handling your claims on priority basis.
You also get some expensive diagnostic
tests.  Apart from that, Heads Up
Tiered Network is the same network advantage
that if you take this option then you will
get some discount.  But you will have to get treatment
within the network itself i.e. within the network preferred network.  If you go
outside,
co-payment will be applicable.  Apart from that,
Voluntary Copayment, Personal Accident,
Hospital Daily Cash, Annual Aggregate
Deductible. If the premium of the policy is getting high
then you can take the policy with deductible.
Claim Safeguard
Well Consult for Non Payable Items This is an OPD
rider.  And borderless if you need to get
treatment outside India then borderless
and borderless for specific illness.  You
can add these riders.  The Elevate has
four zones and the Ratio 3.0 has eight zones
for a premium.  Talking about premium,
I have taken the example of a 35 year old couple
with two kids, Delhi NCR, for
10 years. In Elevate, with Power Booster
Claim Claim Shield, your premium
comes to Rs. 20,000. You get another unique benefit in this,
you get discount on civil.
If your civil is good, then the
premium of Ratio 3.0 is coming to Rs. 22,300.
We can see multi-year policy in both the variants.
You can take a 5-year policy with Ratio 3.0 and Elevate.
This is a very good hedge because
due to inflation the premium keeps increasing,
so you can save a little by taking a multi-year policy.
Talking about claim experience, the
incurred claim ratio of ICICI LB is
82%.  Whereas Niv BPA is 61%, it is
lagging a lot.  7075% is
a good ratio.  This means that they are
charging you more premium but giving you less money.
ICIC is a consistory of LBD.   It is always
above 7075%.  Claim settlement
ratio is slightly lower NIV of ICICI LBAD is
higher than BPA.  Talking about the complaint ratio, out of
10,000 claims,
14 complaints are coming in ICICI LBA and 43 complaints are coming in Niv BPA, which is
almost three times
more complaints.  Talking about value for money,
both are fair valued.  Premium Wise
is quite consistent.  On the basis of these comparisons,
you can decide which
health insurance you want to take.  As
important as it is to get the right health
insurance, it is equally important to get it
from the right place where you can get good after
sales service and
help in claim settlement. If you
want to buy a policy with me, then you can connect by sending a
message on the number given below or by visiting my website
Ashutosh Shukla.com.
Friends, if you liked the video and the
comparison, then do like it
and subscribe to the channel.  If you
want to see comparison of any other health insurance, then let us
know by commenting below.  That's all for today's
video.  See you
in the next video, thanks.